Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
The engine stopped ?!
What about the sub-engine ?
Not good. No response.
All hands, prepare for emergency landing !
Water landing in four…
…three…
…two…
…one…
Landing !
Sorry, Kodai.
Klaus Keyman…
I wonder who he really is ?
The ambassador who invited Kodai to the
Moon must have been a conspirator all along.
But it didn't seem like Keyman
was expecting Desler to be here.
Why did he get on board the Yamato…?
The same as you.
I can't let the Earthlings obtain the power of Telezart.
That's why I came along with them,
and disabled the Yamato when the time was right…
Bring the power of Telezart to Garmillas…
…for the sake of those who oppose democracy
and wish for the restoration of the Desler regime…
It's been a while, Mr. Mill.
It sounded chaotic outside.
Well, a faithless rat was trying
to snatch the Emperor's treasure.
I killed him and took it back.
Telezart is currently under my fleet's control.
The door is open,
so why don't you see for yourself ?
Your job is to observe.
Afterwards I want to begin
negotiations with Emperor Zorder.
I'll humbly hand over
Telezart to the Emperor, but in return…
Do you think they'll agree to negotiate ?
Emperor Zorder isn't concerned about saving face.
Given the risk of losing Teresa by
attacking us, he'll accept my condition.
Discovery or creation of a
planet for Garmillans to survive…
Perhaps Gatlantis can…
Ranhalt.
Sir ?
What was that ship like ?
A strange ship.
And the crew is just as eccentric.
They looked more like pilgrims than soldiers.
Pilgrims, huh ?
Planet Garmillas
His Highness, Ranhalt, has reached Telezart.
He has a lineage of strong luck.
So, does Teresa exist ?
Yes.
The Gatlantis occupational force has been wiped out, and Telezart is under our fleet's control.
Our fleet ? Of whom ?
Of His Excellency Abelt Desler.
H...he's alive ?!
The Desler faction's mastermind has
been kept secret for a long time.
I don't know the person's identity either.
He'll have to come forward and talk face
to face with me under the circumstances.
Your Excellency, we have an incoming
message from the home planet.
You are…
Ghale Desler !
Your Excellency, I'm glad you're alive.
I didn't know you were alive, Gimlay.
"The dictator who lost his mind and tried to destroy the Yamato by sacrificing the capital Ballerus…"
That's how the democratic faction
portrays you, in order to undermine you.
But I know it was unavoidable in
order to save both Garmillas and Iscandar.
Ballerus Tower is the blade pointed at Iscandar.
Those who tried to save Garmillas from
extinction by stealing the Cosmo Reverse...
…developed a massive weapon without your knowledge.
The military betrayed you,
but you out-smarted them…
…and used the Yamato's advancement to separate the core ship, which powered the weapon, from the tower.
Then, to eliminate the traitors, the second Ballerus was…
Everything was for Garmillas'
survival and Iscandar's peace.
Only a dictator's authoritarianism
can open the future for Garmillas.
I thought Ranhalt would be the only one who could
bear the burden of the Führer, but since you are alive…
Ranhalt.
Sir.
You don't mind me taking the role ?
Of course not.
We must inform all Garmillas' citizens
of Führer Desler's return at once.
A revolt has already been prepared.
Please return as soon as possible.
They're like vultures.
In short, it's not a mechanical malfunction.
I don't know the cause, but the wave motion engine has some kind of critical problem.
Strange…
Tsurumi's body is right there, but he's gone.
Where have you gone ?
Teresa…
I'm confused.
The preparations are complete,
and I know what to do, but…
Teresa, if you can see beyond time,
I want you to tell me what's best !
Which path should I take ?
Everything you felt on the Yamato is the truth.
What makes it the best depends on you.
Instead of thoughts, let your feelings guide you.
You are a part of the great harmony.
Great harmony...
What are you doing ?
Führer…
How awkward…
That's the title you wished to bear.
If Teresa could be taken away from here, I'd have to suspect you of betrayal, but…
And you ?
What're you trying to do all by yourself ?
Probably the same as you.
Everyone has a mental pillar of support…
…especially those who can only depend on themselves.
But my support…
In order to move Garmillas' citizens, I was
going to completely terraform a planet, but…
…she offered a helping hand to it.
To save Iscandar, you…
The Cosmo Reverse is not perfect.
Unlike Earth, the planet Garmillas is meant to die, so I'm not sure whether I can save it or not.
I sought a new world outside our galaxy.
As a result…
Well, you already know that.
What was I trying to destroy at that time…?
Führer Desler…
Whatever the reason, I sacrificed
many, many people, and that's a fact.
That sin cannot be atoned for.
If the people of Garmillas want
a Desler, it should be you.
That's…
Excuse me…
There's always someone else in your mind.
You treasure that person more
than anyone, including yourself.
As long as you keep that feeling,
you deserve to lead people.
You talk a lot about things without being asked.
Now, fate appears to be completely linked together.
Teresa…
Chief Hiss, Lieutenant Keyman just contacted me.
Did you find anything ?
The mastermind of the faction conspiring
to restore the Desler regime, is…
…the former Secretary of the Royal Guard, Heidom Gimlay.
Gimlay ? He's alive ?!
I'll arrest him for the dignity of the
Intelligence and Security Bureau.
No regrets…
Hey, you !
What's the meaning of this ?!
Stop, Saito !
What can I…
What can we trust ?
Nothing. There's no truth to the
words from an undercover agent.
Undercover…?
Garmillas Intelligence and Security Bureau
internal affairs division agent.
That's who I am.
Let's head back to the Yamato.
If you want to kill me, do it later.
Revolt ?
Ranhalt went ahead and freed the Earthlings.
Let him do as he likes,
same for the Yamato.
I don't know why, but it suddenly fired up.
But...
...I don't know if we can celebrate this situation.
You might have to issue an evacuation order.
No, we'll fly with what we have.
Shima, prepare for take off !
R…roger.
Chief, is that alright ?
Do what you want !
Ambassador Barrel worked his
way up in the Intelligence Bureau.
He believes democracy will
shape the future of Garmillas.
I've been trying to identify the mysterious
mastermind on the order of the Ambassador.
But you are the Desler family's…
That's the very reason.
I want to lead Garmillas into true democracy.
That's the atonement of a man who's
been born into a family of dictators.
Is that why you got on the Yamato, and guided it to Telezart ?
It was all to gain trust and get to the
mysterious mastermind, and it was a success.
But…
…I was not expecting Desler's appearance.
Why didn't you go with him ?
Especially if the story about the
planet Garmillas' end is true…
Right.
I could have taken that option, but…
…the Goddess taught me that…
…I should let my feelings guide me, rather than thinking.
Message from First Officer Sanada.
Everyone's safe.
Get in, quick !
Keyman !
Yamato, taking off !
Deploy the main wings.
You also chose the unexpected path.
You....!
Such impulsive action will destroy the universe.
Right. I have emotions.
That's why I can do this.
Damn you !
Are you alright with that ?
This is Kodai.
I lost Keyman's ship.
Can you trace it on your end ?
After leaving the enemy vessel, it rapidly
dove to the sea surface. We lost the signal.
Say what ?
Yamamoto is heading
to the location to rescue him.
Is this it ?
I've been alone.
I could do anything by myself, but now…
Mother...
...once again…
I'll rescue him, no matter what !
Over there !
This is Yamamoto.
I've rescued Lieutenant Keyman.
Get the med team ready.
What ?
What's going on ?
Teresa…
Yuki, what's wrong ?
Teresa's asking us not to forget…
Farewell, everyone.
I'll return to where I belong and continue praying.
It's not a fixed location,
and I don't pray for a particular person.
It's unobtainable after all.
Planet and planet, time and time…
…and also person and person.
Fate brings them together to form the field of life.
The force that holds this universe together…
What is this ?
This is…
This is Teresa's…
I entrust my wish to the ship of the
great harmony and will continue praying.
Fate…
…is the love of the universe…?
Well, I'm fine with that.
We know her wish.
We must stop Gatlantis…
…for the sake of all living things in the universe.
Bring us about, all ahead full !
Take the Yamato back to Earth !
Episode 16
Farewell, Teresa! Cast Bouquets for Two Deslers
Sotto oyasuminasai
A gentle goodnight
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Sawamura Sho:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Kokubun Masato
Mugihito
Hirata Daisuke
Tanaka Rie
Shikaki Yuya
Osanago no youna toiki
You breathe like a little child
Saito Hajime:
Nakagura Shiori:
Hijikata Ryu:
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Mill:
Gharder Talan:
Loren Barrel:
Lutz Karzet:
Heidom Gimley:
Redof Hiss:
Nerun Keeling:
Tall Tord:
Rogue Moram:
Teresa:
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Ishizuka Unsho
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Uchiyama Koki
Nakamura Kotaro
Terasoma Masaki
Onozuka Takashi
Morita Junpei
Akimoto Yosuke
Kushida Yasumichi
Fujinuma Kento
Yano Masaaki
Kanda Sayaka
Itsumademo soba ni iru kara
I'll be by your side forever
Mabuta tojite
So close your eyes
Hidamari no takeru youna yasashisa de...
As gentle as warm sunlight...
...Tsusumi komu yo
...I'll embrace you
Shiawase umidasu chikara
The power to bring happiness
Fuwari fuwari fuwa fuwa yume no naka
Drifting and floating, feeling like I'm having a dream
Omoi haseru yorisoinagara
Cuddling up and thinking of you from afar
Itsudemo waratte ite hoshii to negau
My wish is for you to keep on smiling
Never let your childlike smile disappear
Ubu na egao tayasanu youni
Itooshii hito yo...
My dearest one...
Preview
Destroy the Yamato.
At this rate, Garmillas will be destroyed !
Who are you ?
I'm a traitor.
To exterminate all lifeforms including themselves.
Episode 17
Battle of Saturn - Gather the Wave Motion Gun Fleet !